---
title: 'Frequent questions'
frequentQuestion:
    -
        question: 'How can I buy a jewel from Vega Navascués?'
        answer: dasdasdasdasd
    -
        question: 'What characteristics does silver have?'
        answer: "Silver is one of the seven metals known since Antiquity. It is mentioned in the book of Genesis, and the slag heaps found in Asia Minor and islands of the Aegean Sea, indicate that the metal began to separate from lead at least four millennia before our era. Since Hippocrates (s. V a.C  ), the germicidal effect of silver has been known and various remedies for a great variety of diseases have been commercialized and marketed today.\r\nSilver is a chemical element of atomic number 47 located in group 11 of the periodic table of the elements. Its symbol is Ag (it comes from the Latin: argentum, \"white\" or \"bright\"). It is a white transition metal, bright, soft, ductile and malleable.\r\nIt has the highest electrical conductivity and thermal conductivity of all metals, but its higher price has prevented it from being used massively in electrical applications. Pure silver also has the whitest color and the highest reflection rate of all.\r\nExcept for gold, silver is the most malleable and ductile metal. Its hardness varies between 2.5 and 2.7; It is harder than gold, but softer than copper. It has a melting point of 962 ° C, a boiling point of 2,212 ° C and a relative density of 10.5. Its atomic mass is 107,868. From the chemical point of view, silver is not very active. It is insoluble in dilute acids and alkalis, but dissolves in concentrated nitric or sulfuric acid, and does not react with oxygen or water at ordinary temperatures. Sulfur and sulfides attack silver, and tarnish or loss of gloss occurs by the formation of black silver sulfide on the surface of the metal. Eggs, which contain a considerable amount of sulfur as a component of their proteins, tarnish the silver quickly. The small amounts of sulfur that exist in the atmosphere or that are added to domestic natural gas in the form of hydrogen sulfide (H2S), also tarnish the silver. The use of silver in jewelry, tableware and coin minting is well known. The metal is usually alloyed with small amounts of other metals to make it harder and more resistant."
    -
        question: 'What does the term "sterling silver" mean?'
        answer: "The law is a unit of measurement that defines the purity of precious metals, describing the amount of fine gold or silver in bullion, jewelry or coins.\r\nSterling silver, or in English \"Hallmark silver\", is one in which the precious metal enters its composition in the minimum amount set by current legislation. The royal decree published in the BOE of Spain, of 17/1985, of July 1, on objects made of precious metals, establishes the following laws for silver: - 925 sterling silver - 2nd grade silver\r\nThe term 925 sterling silver means that there are 925 grams of silver in every 1000 grams of the product made (alloy contains 92.5% silver).\r\nA product that had a lower percentage of silver would be second-rate silver, and if a product contained less than 80% silver it would not even be legal silver."
    -
        question: ' What types of silver are there?'
        answer: "A higher or lower content of silver in the final product does not mean that it is better (as long as it is sterling silver, of course), although it may be more expensive, since it depends a lot on the type of jewel.\r\nThe different silver alloys are called denominations and are classified according to the percentage of silver they contain:<br>\r\n<strong>Silver .999:</strong>The expressions silver 999, fine silver or in English \"Fine or Pure silver\" are different ways of calling pure silver, that is, silver not alloyed with other metals. Silver 999 means that the product contains 99.9% of silver, therefore, you can not obtain finer silver than this, since the metal always contains some impurity, even in an absolutely minimal amount. For this reason, the term silver 999 reflects reality better than the silver 1000 term.<br>\r\n<strong>Silver .958:</strong> also called \"Britannia Silver\", is little known and rarely used, except in some musical instruments. It is not used much in jewelry because it is too soft.<br>\r\n<strong>Silver .950:</strong> in English \"french 1st standard\" Sterling silver containing 950 grams of silver per 1000 grams of the final product.<br>\r\n<strong>Silver .925:</strong> it is also called sterling silver, first law or in English \"Sterling silver\". It has a silver content of 92.5% and the rest are alloys to give it hardness and thus be more appropriate to make pieces of jewelry. It is the type of silver most used in jewelry and also very common in silver coins.<br>\r\n<strong>Silver .900:</strong> It is a type of silver that is used to make coins, and its use in jewelry is limited because it tends to get black with some ease. It was widely used to make \"bullion\" coins a few decades ago, although at present it is no longer used. Called in English \"Coin silver\", it consists of 900 grams of silver and 100 grams of alloy.<br>\r\n<strong>Silver .800:</strong> called in English \"Egyptian silver\", is an alloy of silver that contains 800 grams of silver and 200 grams of other metals (usually copper) per 1000 grams of final product. This denomination is already considered as a 2nd law.<br>\r\n<strong>Silver .720:</strong> it is a very scarce type of silver, difficult to find at the moment, nevertheless, it was very used to make silver coins in the last century during the first decades. It can be used for the creation of imitation jewelery or jewels, however, they will never have the necessary accreditation to be objects with a high value in the market.<br>\r\n<strong>German silver:</strong> also called alpaca or in English \"German silver\", is NOT silver or contains it, but is an alloy of copper, nickel and zinc. Alpaca products, especially hooks or closures, can cause allergic reactions due to the presence of nickel.<br>\r\n<strong>Tibetan silver:</strong> in English \"Tibetan silver\", also known as Tibetan alloy, is a traditional alloy of Tibet consisting of copper, zinc and other metals (does not contain nickel or lead). In the past, Tibetan silver contained about 30% silver, however, Tibetan silver is currently produced with a minimum silver content or even without silver (most of the Tibetan silver in the current market)."
    -
        question: ' Why is silver oxidized?'
        answer: "Silver is a precious metal of great quality, however, it can undergo changes in its appearance and begin to darken when it undergoes an oxidation process. When we find a piece of oxidized silver, it does not mean that it is of poor quality, since there are many factors that can affect silver.\r\nSilver, like other precious metals such as gold and platinum, does not suffer from atmospheric oxidation. However, the hydrogen sulfide in the environment, together with water and air, can form silver sulfide and the exposed silver begins to take on a yellowish hue and ends up darkening in a process known as oxidation.\r\nHowever, the oxidized silver can be perfectly cleaned and restored to its original appearance without probl"
    -
        question: ' What factors can cause silver to rust?'
        answer: "Not all silver objects behave the same, so there is no formula that we can determine to avoid encountering rusty silver. What we can do is make known some elements that affect this process to happen:\r\nThe PH of the skin. This varies according to the person and, for that reason, it can not be controlled. Thus, there are people with a more acid PH that can accelerate the oxidation process.\r\nThe water in our area. When washing an element, water and its components can influence the oxidation of silver.\r\nMineral-medicinal waters. This type of water usually contains a high sulfur content that spoils the silver.\r\nPerfumes, colognes, chemicals, soaps and cleaning products. All the non-natural components of these products affect the silver until it oxidizes it.\r\nYour storage place. Where we place the silver, near what objects and in what conditions, it affects greatly in its physical composition. According to these characteristics, we can increase or decrease the oxidation time.\r\nThe amount of sulfur in the environment. This factor can not be controlled either, since it depends on many other elements. However, we must bear in mind that the same piece will age faster or slower depending on the area in which we reside."
    -
        question: 'How can I care for a silver piece with patina?'
        answer: 'Silver pieces that have an oxidized or patina finish are not coated on their surface, so you should avoid using any type of substance to polish the silver. Instead, use a dry and clean cloth and avoid scratching the piece.'
    -
        question: 'Are there differences between ring sizes for men and women?'
        answer: 'No, there is no difference between the sizes of men and women.'
    -
        question: 'Is it possible to change the size of a ring?'
        answer: "Jewelers can perfectly adjust the size of a ring in any direction, as long as the difference is not too great.\r\nThis adjustment can leave a visible seam or an invisible weak point, but a professional jeweler can place the defects out of sight."
    -
        question: 'Do all jewelers use the same ring size scale?'
        answer: 'Different countries have different scales of ring sizes so there are different conversion tables.'
    -
        question: 'How can I find out my ring size?'
        answer: "Before taking the measurement of your finger, you must bear in mind that your hand, with an excess of heat, can be dilated and with excessive cold, it contracts. This detail, in some cases, can vary the size of your ring in several numbers. Because of this, it is best to measure your finger at the end of the day as they are hot and their size will be slightly higher than in the morning or when it is cold.\r\nIf you doubt between two sizes, always choose the largest size, since it can be adjusted later if necessary.\r\nIf you want to buy a wide ring, choose a larger size to make it more comfortable, since wide rings fit better on the finger than narrow rings.\r\nIf your knuckle is much larger than the base of your finger, measure the base of your finger and knuckle and select an intermediate size between the two.\r\nThe ring should fit in the finger in a comfortable but tight, so we avoid bothering us and not fall with our daily movements.<br>\r\n<u><strong>Option A:</strong></u><br>\r\nWhen measuring your finger, avoid using a rope as they tend to stretch, which can cause you to get the wrong size.\r\nTake a piece of paper that is more than 1 cm wide and approximately 10 cm long, surround your finger with the paper and mark the starting point and end point on the paper. Subsequently, with a ruler, measure the distance from one to another and you will get the measurement of the contour of your finger in millimeters. For example, 6 cm equals 60 millimeters. With this measure the jeweler can work perfectly.<br>\r\n<u><strong>Option B:</strong></u><br>\r\nThe website https://findmyringsize.com/ offers a very reliable tool to measure the size of the ring very accurately."
    -
        question: 'I already know my ring size, how can I change it to another scale?'
        answer: "There are many online tables with the equivalences between the different scales, but the measures sometimes vary between them, so they are not totally reliable.\r\nYou can find a very precise conversion table between scales at https://findmyringsize.com/en/conversiontable.aspx."
---

